export const typescript = [
    {
        question: "What is TypeScript?",
        option1: "A programming language",
        option2: "A database management system",
        option3: "A web server",
        option4: "A text editor",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "Who developed TypeScript?",
        option1: "Google",
        option2: "Apple",
        option3: "Microsoft",
        option4: "Facebook",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following statements about TypeScript is true?",
        option1: "It is a superset of JavaScript",
        option2: "It is a subset of JavaScript",
        option3: "It is a completely different language from JavaScript",
        option4: "It is an alternative to Python",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "What is the file extension for TypeScript files?",
        option1: ".js",
        option2: ".ts",
        option3: ".html",
        option4: ".css",
        ans: 2,
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used to define types in TypeScript?",
        option1: "type",
        option2: "def",
        option3: "interface",
        option4: "class",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "What does TypeScript offer that JavaScript does not?",
        option1: "Static typing",
        option2: "Dynamic typing",
        option3: "Both static and dynamic typing",
        option4: "No typing",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "What is the purpose of TypeScript's 'strict' mode?",
        option1: "To enforce stricter syntax rules",
        option2: "To allow any type of code",
        option3: "To disable type checking",
        option4: "To make the code more lenient",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used to compile TypeScript code to JavaScript?",
        option1: "tsc",
        option2: "js",
        option3: "typescriptc",
        option4: "compile",
        ans: 1,
    },
    {
        question: "What is the correct syntax to declare an array in TypeScript?",
        option1: "let arr = []",
        option2: "let arr: array[] = []",
        option3: "let arr: Array<number> = []",
        option4: "let arr: Array = []",
        ans: 3,
    },
    {
        question: "What is the purpose of the 'readonly' keyword in TypeScript?",
        option1: "To make a variable immutable",
        option2: "To declare a variable",
        option3: "To allow variable mutation",
        option4: "To define a function",
        ans: 1,
    },
];
